M Usman Maqbool Bhutta

PHD CANDIDATE · DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Room 2008 (25), Robotics Institute, 2nd Floor, CYT Building, Lift(35-36), HKUST

🛮 (+852) 6843-2892 | 🗷 mumbhutta@connect.ust.hk | 🐐 usmanmaqbool.github.io | 🛅 usmanmaqbool | 🖏 usman17888

"Do it with passion or not at all."

Summary

Current co-founder of a start-up company Lisee Technology Corporation. 5+ years experience specializing in project management for research and development, web development and marketing at Friends Corporate Technologies. I have been a part of some other startups related to real estate, marketing, and automation. A super nerd who loves entrepreneurship, deep learning, and enjoys to develop the idea to reality. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises..

Education

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology - HKUST

Ph.D. Candidate, Department of Electronic & Computer Engineering

- Got PEEF Pakistan scholarship to pursuing my studies
- · Research interests; Multi-Agent SLAM System and autonomous car driving

Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

M.PHIL. ELECTRONICS, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS

- · Research: Signal and Image Processing
- Grade: 1st Division (80% Marks)

Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

M.Sc. Electronics, Department of Electronics

- · 2nd position in batch
- Grade: 1 st Division (74.6% marks)

Bahauddin Zakariya University - BZU

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Physics

· Grade: 1st Division

(Kowloon, Hong Kong)

Sep. 2016 - Present

Islamabad, Pakistan Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

Islamabad, Pakistan

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

Multan, Pakistan

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

Research Publications

PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Conference Paper

BHUTTA, M. USMAN MAQBOOL, MING LIU

Jul 2018

Presented in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems, and won **Best Student Paper Finalist Award.**

An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

Bhutta, M. Usman Maqbool, Hasan Mahmood, and Haroon Malik

Jul 2014

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP).

Efficient Reset Design Techniques

Journal Paper

Qamar, Zoha, Bushra Yaseen, and Usman Maqbool

2015

Published in Science International Lahore

Work Experience

INDUSTRY

Friends Corporate Technologies

Islamabad, PK

D Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

Federal Government of Pakistan

Islamabad, PK May 2012 - Feb 2013

Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

Server4Sale, LLC Islamabad, PK

PHP Developer

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

ACADEMIC

Department of Computer Science

BZU sub campus Sahiwal, PK

LECTURER (VISITING)

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

Department of Physics

Government PG College Sahiwal, PK

CT

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

Aug. 2014 - Apr. 2016

Academic Activities _____

2018	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	IROS 2018
S 2018	Teaching Assistant , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
S 2017	Teaching Assistant, ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Jı	July 2010	Best Student Paper Finalist Award, IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and	Tianjin, China
	July, 2018	Intelligent Systems	riarijiri, Criiria
	May, 2018	Best Proposal Audience Award, Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST	HKUST, HK
	Nov, 2017	Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
	May, 2017	Completion Award, The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST	HKUST, HK
	Dec, 2016	Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
	Nov, 2016	Completion Award, Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus	HKUST, HK

DOMESTIC

Participant, Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative	Islamabad, PK			
Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition	Islamabad, PK			
Participant, Case EPICA	Islamabad, PK			
Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK			
Participant, Punjab Youth Festival	Lahore, PK			
Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival	Islamabad, PK			
Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival	Lahore, PK			
Completion Award, Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK			
Participant, National Drama Festival	Islamabad, PK			
Instuctor of short Course , PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU	Islamabad, PK			
Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan	Mansehra, PK			
Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club	Islamabad, PK			
Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU	Islamabad, PK			
	Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition Participant, Case EPICA Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan Participant, Punjab Youth Festival Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival Completion Award, Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan Participant, National Drama Festival Instuctor of short Course, PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club			